Satyam Mishra

satyamgusmishra@gmail.com • 857-701-3819 • Boston, MA • Linkedin

SUMMARY

2 years 3 months of Data Engineering and Data Science work experience using Python, C++, SQL, and AWS

SKILLS

Programming: C++, R, Bash, Python (Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, NLTK, PySpark, Sklearn, Tensorflow)
Tools/Frameworks: ETL, AWS, Glue, Cloudwatch, Lambda, Vault, Spark, Hadoop, Data Modeling, Git, CI/CD, Docker Databases: MySQL, Postgres, SQLite, NoSQL, MongoDB, Apache Cassandra, SSMS, S3, Redshift, Airflow, OLAP, OLTP Analytics: Tableau, EDA, Hypothesis Testing, A/B Testing, Market-Basket Analysis, Statistics, Dimensional Modeling

Experience

Data Engineer at TransUnion

Aug 2022 - Present

- Implemented ETL pipelines on 9 data sources using in-house variation of C++ (codex) and AWS Redshift.
- Wrote a data pipeline while complying with GLBA and CCPR for a data source of 340 Million customers.
- Assisted in writing Python DAGs to trigger ETL operations on data pipelines every 24 hours with Airflow.
- Collaborated with data scientists on a credit scoring ML model, beating previous accuracy by 9%.
- Used envelope encryption (AES-256) on existing scripts with AWS Vault and C++ using KEK and DEK.
- Wrote and managed 4 Bash scripts in testing, development and production environments.
- Undertook the task of upgrading and testing Codex 9.2 to 9.3 while adhering to data quality checks.
- Ensured timely DDX builds every week and helped in automating distributed processing in PySpark.

Data Science and Analytics Coop at Unum

Jul 2021 to Dec 2021

- Automated a pipeline to stage data from S3 to Redshift, transformed, and connected to Tableau for real-time analysis of mental health status of users majorly based on PHQ-9 and GAD-7 scores.
- Implemented data models, including ER diagrams and dimensional models on raw data sources.
- Used Kafka messaging service to improve feed flow within internal applications.
- Performed data quality checks using Pandas, then EDA in Tableau & statistical analysis on 540000 records.
- Used AWS Lambda with API gateway in Python to initiate triggers to calculate results on 3 events.

Data Science Intern at Eletech Engineering

Jan 2020 to Jun 2020

- Used PyTesseract to create OCR model to digitize database, migrated it on S3 for optimal ETL with Boto3.
- Implemented dimensionality reduction with PCA and LASSO on impact metrics data and created new KPIs.
- Used K-Means clustering model for segregation of faulty manufactured components on impact metrics.
- Analyzed feedback of 10000 deliveries, followed by deploying BERT base classifier to assist marketing.

PROJECTS

Healthcare Data Analytics Platform on MIMIC-III Data

- Used Hadoop for secure and scalable storage of healthcare data and EMR for parallel data processing.
- Implemented data anonymization (PII) with PySpark and Hadoop ensuring HIPAA regulations.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Data Analytics Engineering, Northeastern University

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science Engineering, Medicaps University

May 2022 Jul 2020